<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on Emir Demić</title>
    <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on Emir Demić</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Acute Inflammation of Urinary Bladder and Acute Nephritis (In Progress)</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>The main goal of this project is to create a Machine Learning model using small dataset generated by medical experts in order to predict acute inflammation of urinary bladder and acute nephritises. Acute inflammation of urinary bladder is characterised by a sudden occurence of pain in the abdomen region and the urination in form of constant urine pushing, micturition pains, and sometimes lack of urine keeping, while acute nephritis begins with a sudden fever accompanied by shivers and lumbar pain which can be very strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titanic - Predicting Passengers&#39; Survival (In Progress)</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>The sinking of Titanic on April 15, 1912 is certainly a well-known event which led to a death of 1502 out of 2224 passengers and crew. Surviving the collision was not the result of pure lack or chance - some factors led to a more likely survival of some passengers. Some of those factors certainly are gender and age (&amp;ldquo;Women and children first!&amp;rdquo; - as depicted by Titanic movie). The goal of this project is to explore available data on passengers and to develop a machine learning model which would predict whether a particular passenger survived or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Employee Turnover</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Since employee turnover poses a great issue for companies and organizations regardless of their size, the goal of this project was to develop, evaluate and choose the best model for predicting whether employee will leave the company or not. The goal was accomplished by training several different estimators, tuning hyperparameters and developing more complex ensemble models. The final model achieved an accuracy of 99% on test data! Conclusions and implications are discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replicating Patterns of Prospect Theory for Decision Under Risk</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Co-authored the paper Replicating patterns of prospect theory for decision under risk published in Nature Human Behaviour. The topic of research was highly influential theory of decision making and it was conducted in 19 different countries with more than 4000 subjects! The research was carried out from University of Cambridge. The paper was published on May 18, 2020 and has already been covered by different sites, news, newspapers and institutions, such as Wikipedia, University of Cambridge, Nature, University of Columbia, Arstechnica, Brainpost, RTS, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Chinook Music Store Database Using PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this ongoing project is to explore the Chinook Database which consists of data on customers and their purchases in the Chinook music store. A few insights gatheres so far, which could drive future bussiness decisions and strategies, include the performance of employees in retail, average order value per country, top-selling genres, and whether customers by whole albums or individual tracks.
This is still an ongoing project, and the current notebook version is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the Explanation for Phonological Similarity Effect</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Phonological similarity effect refers to an observation that the recall of phonologically similar letters is worse than of those which are not similar. The effect was tested in multiple settings and seems to be highly robust. One potential explanation which was not extensively tested is that similar letters do not have discriminative retrieval cues, which leads to their poor recall. In this experiment, co-authored by Ana Avramović and Milica Šimonović and presented in Belgrade and Cambridge, the explanation was put to a direct test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing and Validating the Masculinity Scale</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Developed and validated scale which measures masculinity in collaboration with 4 colleagues of mine. During the first phase of this year-long project, a thorough literature review was conducted and specific subscales and items were constructed. Developed questionnaire was tested on a sample of 320 participants and results indicated which items should be excluded. The second phase consisted of checking construct, predictive, and diagnostic validity. For those purposes, a number of other scales were used as well, including those measuring agression, attitudes towards feminism, and HEXACO personality questionanire!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating and Validating General Risk Propensity Scale</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Researchers interested in risk propensity traditionally considered risk taking as a domain-specific phenomenon. However, there is an evidence suggesting that risk taking could be considered as a general trait which could be measured by diffent techniques, among which are self-report questionnaires. Zhang and colleagues (2018) developed a short questionnaire for measuring general risk propensity. In this small project, the goal was to translate the scale into Serbian language, check its reliability, and explore its structural validity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emirdemic.github.io/Personal-Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you want to contact me, you can send me an e-mail: s.dg.emir@gmail.com!
I will try and respond as quikly as possible! :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>